Support Admin Watch on kissasia.cam or kisskh.org
دعم الإدارة، شاهد على kissasia.cam أو kisskh.org
=Phoenix's Homecoming=
=عودة فينيكس إلى الوطن=
=Episode 7=
=الحلقة 7=
Bring me the brush.
أحضر لي الفرشاة.
Cheng.
تشنغ.
What do you think?
ماذا تعتقد؟
(The Reign of Yao and Shun)
(عهد ياو وشون)
Isn't this the Grand Princess' handwriting?
أليس هذا خط يد الأميرة الكبرى؟
(It's him after all.)
(إنه هو في النهاية.)
(As my personal secretary,)
(بصفتي سكرتيرتي الشخصية،)
(he's skilled at imitating)
(إنه بارع في التقليد)
(my handwriting.)
(خط يدي.)
All of you, get out.
اخرجوا جميعاً.
I want to live.
أريد أن أعيش.
Die!
ال!
Stay back.
ابقَ بعيداً.
Jia Cheng.
جيا تشنغ.
I have come to see you.
لقد جئت لرؤيتك.
Your Highness?
سموكم؟
Your Highness.
صاحب السمو.
Since ancient times, beauties and famed generals
منذ العصور القديمة، الجميلات والقادة العسكريون المشهورون
are not meant to show the toll of years to mortal eyes.
لا يُقصد بها إظهار أثر السنين على عيون البشر.
You are growing old here.
أنت تتقدم في السن هنا.
But I have been
لكنني كنت
terribly lonely in the underworld.
أشعر بوحدة شديدة في العالم السفلي.
Jia Cheng,
جيا تشنغ,
have you forgotten
هل نسيت؟
who brought you into the palace?
من أدخلك إلى القصر؟
How dare you betray me?
كيف تجرؤ على خيانتي؟
Kill him for me now.
اقتله من أجلي الآن.
Pay for my master's death.
ادفع ثمن موت سيدي.
Sheng Yunlin.
شنغ يونلين.
Are you a vengeful ghost from the underworld?
هل أنت شبح انتقامي من العالم السفلي؟
Lord Jia killed someone!
اللورد جيا قتل شخصاً ما!
Help!
يساعد!
Let's go.
دعنا نذهب.
Blood!
دم!
A body!
جثة!
Why would he kill his own retainer?
لماذا يقتل أحد أتباعه؟
Stop staring. Report to the authorities.
توقف عن التحديق. أبلغ السلطات.
Report it now.
أبلغ عنه الآن.
How am I
كيف حالي؟
going to run my business?
هل سيديرون أعمالي؟
Oh, my heavens!
يا إلهي!
Where is the killer?
أين القاتل؟
He already vanished so soon.
لقد اختفى بالفعل بهذه السرعة.
Search. He couldn't have gone far.
ابحث. لا يمكن أن يكون قد ذهب بعيداً.
To make them fall out,
لإخراجهم من دائرة الخلاف،
you must corner them first.
يجب عليك محاصرتهم أولاً.
Once they fall out,
بمجرد أن ينفصلوا،
the mastermind shows up.
يظهر العقل المدبر.
To spare a rival invites a future doom.
إن إبقاء المنافس على قيد الحياة يستدعي هلاكاً في المستقبل.
Lure the snake, and seal its tomb.
استدرج الأفعى، وأغلق قبرها.
The Ghost Fire killed his retainer today.
تسبب حريق الشبح في مقتل مساعده اليوم.
What a great show.
يا له من عرض رائع.
They're after you.
إنهم يلاحقونك.
Our cooperation ends here.
ينتهي تعاوننا هنا.
Leave.
يترك.
I disagree.
أنا أعترض.
(Chancellor, Huo Chengyun)
(المستشار، هيو تشينغ يون)
The assassination failed. I await punishment.
فشلت محاولة الاغتيال. أنتظر العقاب.
The Prince of Qi had a woman by his side.
كان أمير تشي برفقة امرأة.
Great martial artist.
فنان قتالي عظيم.
She looks exactly like the Grand Princess.
إنها تشبه الأميرة الكبرى تماماً.
(The Grand Princess?)
(الأميرة الكبرى؟)
(Wedding of the New Emperor Chen Yu)
(زفاف الإمبراطور الجديد تشن يو)
Yuan!
يوان!
Sheng Yunlin!
شنغ يونلين!
Mark my words.
تذكروا كلامي.
I'll kill you with my own hands.
سأقتلك بيدي.
It's His Majesty's wedding.
إنه حفل زفاف جلالته.
Chancellor Huo's son, Huo Yuan,
نجل المستشار هوو، هوه يوان
harassed me first
لقد تحرش بي أولاً
then attempted to murder me.
ثم حاول قتلي.
To protect myself,
لحماية نفسي،
I executed him on the spot.
أعدمته في الحال.
Should anyone object,
في حال اعتراض أي شخص،
it would be disloyalty and disrespect toward
سيكون ذلك خيانة وعدم احترام تجاه
His Majesty.
صاحب الجلالة.
I failed to discipline my son.
لقد فشلت في تأديب ابني.
I am guilty.
أنا مذنب.
I beg Your Highness for forgiveness.
أرجو من سموكم الصفح.
Really?
حقًا؟
Absolutely.
قطعاً.
It's all because of
كل ذلك بسبب
that woman...
تلك المرأة...
Chancellor, he mentioned the Grand Princess.
يا مستشار، لقد ذكر الأميرة الكبرى.
The Grand Princess
الأميرة الكبرى
simply wouldn't let go.
لم يكن ليتركني ببساطة.
Is there something behind it?
هل هناك شيء ما وراء ذلك؟
Recently,
حديثاً،
several murders have occurred.
وقعت عدة جرائم قتل.
Feng Yuan and Xue Ruoliu
فنغ يوان و شيويه روليو
perished in phosphorescent flames.
هلكوا في ألسنة اللهب المتوهجة.
Su Wei died in a fire caused by lightning.
توفي سو وي في حريق نجم عن صاعقة برق.
All fire-related.
جميعها متعلقة بالحرائق.
History is written by the victors.
التاريخ يكتبه المنتصرون.
In this lifetime's chess game,
في لعبة الشطرنج هذه التي تدور أحداثها في الحياة،
I have narrowly won by half a move.
لقد فزت بصعوبة بنصف نقلة.
But I respect an opponent like you,
لكنني أحترم خصماً مثلك،
who made the game more satisfying.
من جعل اللعبة أكثر إرضاءً.
Enjoy the wine
استمتع بالنبيذ
on your way
في طريقك
to the underworld.
إلى العالم السفلي.
It seems someone is plotting
يبدو أن أحدهم يخطط لشيء ما
to do the Grand Princess justice.
لكي ننصف الأميرة الكبرى.
Fine.
بخير.
Then I will
ثم سأفعل
take you all down.
سأقضي عليكم جميعاً.
Sheng Yunlin,
شنغ يونلين،
how many lives do you think you have?
كم عدد الأرواح التي تعتقد أن لديك؟
Bear with it.
تحمّل الأمر.
Your medicine
دوائك
works remarkably well.
يعمل بشكل جيد للغاية.
Why haven't you ever shared it with me?
لماذا لم تشاركني إياه من قبل؟
The medicine wasn't ready yet,
لم يكن الدواء جاهزاً بعد،
and you were already gone.
وكنت قد رحلت بالفعل.
I've stirred the court
لقد أثرت ضجة في المحكمة
and was in grave danger
وكان في خطر شديد
due to the schemers.
بسبب المتآمرين.
I've also drawn the bow,
لقد سحبت القوس أيضاً،
fought on battlefields, and survived against all odds,
قاتلوا في ساحات المعارك، ونجوا رغم كل الصعاب.
expecting only to die wrapped in horsehide.
لا يتوقعون سوى الموت ملفوفين بجلد حصان.
But I have never been
لكنني لم أكن كذلك قط
as afraid
خائف
as I am now.
كما أنا الآن.
All this...
كل هذا...
I was consumed by fire, but it felt like a dream.
لقد التهمتني النيران، لكن الأمر بدا وكأنه حلم.
When I awoke,
عندما استيقظت،
I was in a performance troupe.
كنتُ عضواً في فرقة استعراضية.
The manager beat me at will.
كان المدير يضربني متى شاء.
Then, I tried to seek refuge
ثم حاولت البحث عن ملجأ
at the Chaohuang Academy,
في أكاديمية تشاوهوانغ،
only to find everything had changed.
لأجد أن كل شيء قد تغير.
I've been wandering around.
لقد كنت أتجول في الأنحاء.
It's only normal to have some wounds.
من الطبيعي أن يكون لديك بعض الجروح.
You didn't
لم تفعل
come find me
تعال وابحث عني
because you didn't trust me?
لأنك لم تثق بي؟
This is the path I must walk,
هذا هو الطريق الذي يجب أن أسلكه،
even if it's paved with thorns,
حتى لو كانت الطريق مرصوفة بالأشواك،
even if demons block the way.
حتى لو اعترضت الشياطين الطريق.
I will tread over them all.
سأدوس عليهم جميعاً.
Since Heaven has granted me a second chance at life,
بما أن السماء قد منحتني فرصة ثانية في الحياة،
I swear I will
أقسم أنني سأفعل
discover the truth on my own.
أكتشف الحقيقة بنفسي.
How is she?
كيف حالها؟
She's fine.
هي بخير.
Go back and rest.
ارجع واسترح.
Is she badly hurt?
هل هي مصابة بجروح خطيرة؟
If you could defend yourself,
إذا استطعت الدفاع عن نفسك،
she would...
كانت ستفعل...
I'm fine.
أنا بخير.
Sit.
يجلس.
We need to talk.
نحتاج إلى التحدث.
Why did you risk your life for me?
لماذا خاطرت بحياتك من أجلي؟
Aren't we partners?
ألسنا شركاء؟
Besides,
بجانب،
I saved the Seventeenth Prince of Qi.
لقد أنقذت الأمير السابع عشر من مملكة تشي.
This deal
هذه الصفقة
is hardly a loss, right?
ليس خسارة على الإطلاق، أليس كذلك؟
My people reported that
أفاد رجالي بأن
the assassins were Chancellor Huo's shadow guards.
كان القتلة هم حراس الظل للمستشار هو.
So they were after you, Seventeenth Prince.
إذن كانوا يلاحقونك أيها الأمير السابع عشر.
Quite popular with assassins, huh?
يحظى بشعبية كبيرة بين القتلة، أليس كذلك؟
My lady,
سيدتي،
if you want to talk about this,
إذا كنت ترغب في التحدث عن هذا،
then I won't hide anything.
إذن لن أخفي أي شيء.
Qi State faces internal strife.
تواجه دولة تشي صراعاً داخلياً.
King Liang and the Crown Prince are locked in conflict.
الملك ليانغ وولي العهد في صراع محتدم.
So, you...?
إذن، أنت...؟
I side with the Crown Prince.
أنا أؤيد ولي العهد.
Otherwise, why would
وإلا، فلماذا؟
King Liang's lackey,
خادم الملك ليانغ،
Chancellor Huo, send assassins?
هل سيرسل المستشار هوو قتلة؟
So the traitor
إذن الخائن
is him.
هو هو.
That's right.
هذا صحيح.
Can the Chen State
هل تستطيع ولاية تشين
truly withstand the Qi State?
هل يستطيع حقاً الصمود أمام حالة تشي؟
Your Crown Prince advocates peace.
ولي عهدكم يدعو إلى السلام.
Only King Liang
الملك ليانغ فقط
lusts for power and war.
شهوة السلطة والحرب.
Seventeenth Prince,
الأمير السابع عشر،
you support the Crown Prince.
أنت تدعم ولي العهد.
Surely you don't want wars, right?
بالتأكيد لا تريدون الحروب، أليس كذلك؟
Of course not.
بالطبع لا.
After all, my fair Grand Princess
على كل حال، يا أميرتي الجميلة
has returned.
لقد عاد.
Since you know that she's
بما أنك تعلم أنها
the Grand Princess,
الأميرة الكبرى،
address her respectfully as
خاطبها باحترام كما
"Your Highness".
"صاحب السمو".
Hands off me.
ابتعد عني.
My lady, look at him.
سيدتي، انظري إليه.
I hate schemes and court politics.
أكره المؤامرات والسياسة القضائية.
I'd even marry into Chen as Prince Consort,
بل إنني سأتزوج من تشين بصفتي الأمير القرين،
and never attend court.
ولا يحضر المحكمة أبداً.
I just don't get it.
أنا لا أفهم ذلك.
Some people
بعض الناس
rejected the marriage proposal. Huh?
رفض عرض الزواج. هاه؟
So curious.
أمرٌ مثيرٌ للفضول.
I don't think you're badly injured
لا أعتقد أن إصابتك خطيرة
since you're so talkative.
بما أنك كثير الكلام.
I could totally
أستطيع تماماً
administer some poison to the dressing you need to change every three days.
ضع بعض السم في الضمادة التي تحتاج إلى تغييرها كل ثلاثة أيام.
Let go.
اتركه.
Since you treated my lady's wound,
بما أنك قمت بمعالجة جرح سيدتي،
I'll tell you
سأخبرك
what truly caused the Chen State's defeat back then.
ما الذي تسبب فعلاً في هزيمة ولاية تشين آنذاك؟
♪The wind rises, snow falls♪
♪تهب الرياح، ويتساقط الثلج♪
♪To stain endless remorse with red♪
♪لتلطيخ الندم الذي لا ينتهي باللون الأحمر♪
♪No regrets in moves made. Let the game unfold♪
لا ندم على الخطوات التي اتخذتها. دع اللعبة تتكشف.
♪Sorrow and joy intertwined♪
♪الحزن والفرح متشابكان♪
♪Yet we can't escape karma♪
♪لكننا لا نستطيع الهروب من الكارما♪
♪Lament this fleeting life♪
♪رثوا هذه الحياة الزائلة♪
♪So elusive♪
♪مراوغ للغاية♪
♪So indistinct♪
♪غير واضح للغاية♪
♪Resent farewells♪
♪وداعات حزينة♪
♪Remembering each other♪
♪نتذكر بعضنا البعض♪
♪Love can't be extinguished♪
♪الحب لا ينطفئ♪
♪Unwilling to accept♪
♪غير راغب في القبول♪
♪Rewriting the story♪
♪إعادة كتابة القصة♪
♪And praying♪
♪والصلاة♪
♪A long-cherished wish♪
أمنية طالما تمنيتها
♪In a daze♪
♪في حالة ذهول♪
♪Suddenly it's those years again♪
♪فجأة تعود تلك السنوات من جديد♪
♪How I wish to relive my old dreams♪
♪كم أتمنى أن أعيش أحلامي القديمة من جديد♪
♪Rewrite those torn pages♪
♪أعد كتابة تلك الصفحات الممزقة♪